Finding Aid for Shirine M. Repucci papers, 2003-2004
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Shirine M. Repucci papers 2003-2004
Repucci, Shirine M.
0.5 linear feet
2008092 Aa
Shirine M. Repucci served as Coordinator of MichNet recruitment for Merit Network, and wrote a Master's thesis at Eastern Michigan University, entitled "Women's Role in the Development of the Internet and the Social Movement They Propelled." Collection includes tape recordings and typed transcripts of interviews with staff from Merit Network, and National Science Foundation NSFNet, as well as Repucci's Master's thesis.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The records were received from Shirine Repucci (Donor No. 9724 ) in April 2006.
No further additions to the papers are expected.
The collection is open to research.
Shirine M. Repucci wrote her Master's Thesis, entitled "Women's Role in the Development of the Internet and the Social Movement They Propelled" in 2004 for Eastern Michigan University. Previously, she served as Coordinator of MichNet recruitment for Merit Network, an organization established in 1966 to facilitate networked computing on large research universities.
Repucci has contributed articles to the Encyclopedia of Gender and Information Technology.
The Repucci Collection consists of three series relating to her research on women's roles in the development of the internet: interviews on cassette tape; transcripts of these interviews, along with consent forms; and Repucci's Master's thesis based on the interviews, entitled, "Women's Role in the Development of the Internet and the Social Movement They Propelled."
The following were interviewed by Repucci:
Eric Aupperle, Director of Merit from 1974-2001
Jane Caviness, Program Director, NSFNet
Elise Gerich, Associate Director for National Networking at Merit
Susan Hares, Internet Engineer at Merit, 1988-2001
Ellen Hoffman, Manager of User Services at Merit
Jo Ann Ward, Computer Systems Consultant at Merit, 1988-
Stephen Wolff, Division Chief, NSFNet
Jessica Yu, co-Principle Investigator at Merit; Engineer, NSFNet
Subjects:
Internet--History.; Merit Network, Inc.; Repucci, Shirine M.; Women in computer science.
Contributors:
Auperle, Eric M.; Cavines, Jane.; Gerich, Elise.; Hares, Susan.; Hoffman, Ellen.; Ward, Joann.; Wolff, Stephen.; Yu, Jessica.
Genre Terms:
Audiocassettes.
- Audio Recordings
  - Interviews on Audio Cassettes
    - Eric Aupperle, 2/21/2003 (Box 1)
    - Jane Caviness, 5/1/2003 (Box 1)
    - Elise Gerich, 10/17/2003 (Box 1)
    - Susan Hares, 2/14/2003 (Box 1)
    - Ellen Hoffman, 2/23/2003 (Box 1)
    - JoAnn Ward, 2/7/2003 (Box 1)
    - Steve Wolff, 10/24/2003 (Box 1)
  - Transcripts of Interviews (with Participant Consent Forms)
    - Eric Aupperle, Director of Merit (Box 1)
    - Elise Gerich, Associate Director for National Networking at Merit (Box 1)
    - Ellen Hoffman, Manager of User Services at Merit (Box 1)
    - JoAnn Ward, Computer Systems Consultant at Merit (Box 1)
    - Jane Caviness, Program Director, NSFNet (Box 1)
    - Jessica Yu, co-Principle Investigator at Merit; Engineer, NSFNet (Box 1)
    - Stephen Wolff, Division Chief, NSFNet (Box 1)
    - Susan Hares, Internet Engineer at Merit (Box 1)
- Master's Thesis
  - "Women's Role in the Development of the Internet and the Social Movement They Propelled," March 2004 (Box 1)